free-tarot-reading.net 2018-12-27

# Privacy Policy @ Lotus Tarot

#### _We at LT don’t like our personal data being used in ways we don’t know about, and we particularly dislike unrequested marketing, probably just as much as you!_

So, since we launched the website in 2002, we have never sold user data to anyone at all, and that will not change, and the only emails you’ll receive from us are ones you’ve actually requested.

However, the GDPR regulations which went into effect on May 25, 2018 require us to let you know exactly what personal information we collect about you, and what we do with that information. Fortunately for us, that’s a very simple thing to do, because we only collect and store on our database the bare minimum of data we need in order to provide you with the service you choose to use.

#### First the summary:

We will continue to uphold the spirit of privacy by never selling your personal data and by keeping it safe and secure. We will continue to operate a policy of providing a genuinely free and intentionally valuable website service, with options to pay for upgrades or advanced services if you so desire, without the usual hassle of worrying there may be some catch or hidden motivation.

You will only ever receive emails from us when you have asked for them or as confirmation of a registration or product purchase, or on the rare occasion we may need to send you an administration email that concerns your particular Lotus Tarot account.

As part of our free reading service, and ONLY if you have opted for it, we will email you once each week (or more frequently if you specifically request it) with information about the tarot cards in order to enhance your reading experience with us. You can stop these emails at any time by logging into your account and switching Lotus Mail to 'OFF', or using the unsubscribe link which is included in the footer of every such email we send.

If you have any concerns about your privacy, or if you ever receive spam or junk email from someone claiming to be from Lotus Tarot, then please click here to report it to our webmaster.

#### Now the details:

Users who choose to access the general site content and free readings only, and who do not create an account with Lotus Tarot, do not need to provide us with any data at all, so if that is your chosen method to use the website, we don’t have any of your personal data.

Users who choose to create a free account with us do so by providing an email address, a password, a screen name and a date of birth. 

The email address is used as the unique identifier for your account, and also to send you any important notices about your account. If you choose to opt-in to our Lotus Mail service, then we use your email address to send you emails weekly, or on an alternative time frame that you set in your user profile settings. Because of the volume of the emails we send out, and in order to ensure we deliver them reliably and efficiently, we use an email-sending service to do this called SparkPost. Obviously, in order to do their job, SparkPost are provided with your email address. 

Your password is stored in an encrypted form, so even in the unlikely event of a security breach of our database (which has never happened in LT’s history online), your password is not readable and should be perfectly secure. 

The screen name you choose is simply used to address you on the website and in emails by a name you like to be called. Your d.o.b is used to calculate your numerology life path number for you, and to send you a happy birthday email once a year if you opted in to Lotus Mail. 

Anyone who purchases a product from the website must create a user account, and the purchase transaction is also saved to the database with your account details. If you purchase a physical product (like the Lotus Tarot Deck) we require a ship-to address and that is obviously also saved with your account. We do not collect or store any financial data. 

We also store the IP address of registered users when they register and log in. This is basically a standard function of the coding framework which Lotus Tarot is built upon, and the only occasional use we may at some point make of it would be as an aid to assisting users with customer service issues, or perhaps in protecting against malicious users. 

If you use our contact form to send us a message, this creates a message ‘ticket’ on our system which stores the data you entered into the contact form, so that we can read your message and reply to it. 

With the exception of SparkPost who send out our emails for us, and the technical support administrators of our webhost, no other third party has access to any of the data we store as far as we are aware. 

You may contact us at any time and request we delete your account and all your personal data, or you can do this yourself by using the ‘Delete My Account’ button in your account settings. 

#### Cookies:

We use several cookies on the site:

1\. A session cookie: This is required to operate a ‘log-in’ scenario, and basically contains any data or information we need to be able to provide the reading service, and also to remember any site preferences you have set. Logging out of the site deletes this cookie. 

2\. Remember me cookie: If you check the 'remember me' box, you will get another little cookie added to your browser to let it know to log into Lotus Tarot automatically. Again, logging out will destroy this cookie. 

2\. Google Analytics: Like the vast majority of websites, we use the Google Analytics service to gain valuable insight as to how people are using Lotus Tarot. Google uses a cookie to track your usage of the site and build a statistical picture across the entire traffic flow. 

3\. Social Media like and share widgets: Due to popular demand from our users, we have provided buttons to like and share readings and other content of the site on various social media platforms. These widgets may employ their own cookies. 

4\. Kasamba cookie: Our Live Readings service is powered by Kasamba.com. If you use the service by visiting our Live Readings page, you'll receive a cookie that allows Kasamba to know that you have been referred to them from Lotus Tarot.
